Hey everyone, welcome
to the content video
going over section 2.6
and 2.8 of your textbook.
We're going to talk about getting input
from the user and also dynamic typing.
So getting input from the user is
kind of a next step in the process
of like, we can do math, we can
manipulate strings, we can do
all of these things. So what do
we do next? We get input from our
user, we start interacting, right?
So that's what the input function
will do. And it works pretty
simply. We create some kind of a
variable and then we prompt the
user for a response and then we save
their response to that variable.
And then we can start doing
things with that variable. And we'll
do an example in just a minute.
Our user has to hit enter in
order to return something to
the input function. and this
is an important distinction.
The input function will
always, always, always, always
return a string no matter
what our user gives us. So
let's jump over to our
environment and do some examples.
Oh my gosh, I cannot type.
Input.
Okay, so let's get some user input.
Let's make a variable, we'll
call it name and we will
assign it to the return
value of the input function.
And in the input function,
what you usually do is you
prompt the user for some kind
of an input, right? So what
we're going to say in this
case is enter your first name.
And then I like to leave a little
bit of a space there so that
when they type it in the console,
it's not concatenating up
against the input. And then
let's print out their response.
Actually, let's run this code first.
just so we can see what happens.
Did I type something
wrong? No, I didn't. I just
wrote, okay, here it is,
right here at the bottom.
Enter your first name. Well, my
first name is Professor, obviously.
So I'm going to enter Professor
and hit enter, and nothing happens,
unsurprisingly, because there's
nothing else that we told our
code to do. So what we're going to
do with our responses, let's just
return it to the user. so we'll
just print it out to the console.
Your name is name.
So let's run this again. Enter your
first name and again mine's professor.
It's a really boring name and
then here it is your name is
professor. Excellent that's exactly
what I wanted to have happen.
So like I said input function
always returns a string so
we can verify this by using the
type function. So let's print
out type of name. Now the type
function what it does to us is
it returns the class of the
variable that we input to it. So in
this case we are going to input
the name variable into the
type function and then we want it
printed out to us in the console.
So if I run this, enter first
name. Okay, I'm changing it.
It's my first name now. You
can see that the class of
my object, and we'll go over
objects at another point in
this semester, but the class
of my object is a string.
So that means that the type or
whatever this variable, yeah,
type is, is string. So let's
do another example. Let's get
age because that's a number,
right? So let's get input from
our user. So I'm going to make
a variable, I'll call it age.
And we're going to say,
enter your age.
And then what I want to do
is I want to print out the
type of age. So I want to
know what type of variable age
is. So let's run our code.
Oh, first name, that's G now.
My age, well, that's a secret. So
I'm just going to enter 45 because
there we go. Now notice how age
is still a string. So what do
we do about that? Well, we're
going to kind of jump over to our
next section of the textbook to
talk about that. So dynamic typing.
Python is a really cool language
because it is interpreted,
meaning that we can change our
variable types at any time throughout
the code and Python will
be okay with that. In other
languages, what you have to do
is you have to initialize your
variables and very clearly state
what type of variable they are.
And they, generally speaking,
state that type of variable
throughout the code. But
Python is different because
we have dynamic typing,
which is a really fun idea.
So dynamic typing means
that at a basic level, our
variables can change
types throughout the code.
I think I kind of just
said that. So, for example,
type 7 here, actually,
let me run this code.
Let's just put a variable
or a value in here, type
7. So, print out the type
of the value 7 right here.
Let me comment out some of this
other code so we don't have
to get that run every time.
So, type 7 is an integer. And
then let's put in a different
variable value here. Let's
type in true. So what's the
type of true? That's a boolean.
Let's do one more. 3.14.
That should hopefully give us
float. Yep, and it did. So all
of these different types are
what we're kind of working with.
But let's scroll down a little bit
more to this idea of dynamic typing.
So Python uses dynamic typing so it
determines the type of the object
of a variable while executing your
code and you can rebind the variable
to different objects and check their
types as you go. So for example,
here we have a variable x, that's
an integer, and then we change x to
4.1. So the type of x here is a float,
and then we change x to a string
to the value dog, and then we print
out the type here, and the value
is now a string. So this demonstrates
dynamic typing, the fact that a
variable can change over the course
of its lifetime. Now what happens
to those old assignments of x right
here and right here? They go away
into garbage collection as I think
we've mentioned in a previous video.
So garbage collection just clears
up objects from memory that aren't
being used anymore so that we have
available memory for new objects. So
let's do some examples of dynamic
typing and I'll show you kind of why
we use this in real code. So let's
say that we have a value, let's call
it pi, and we want the user to input
pi. So we'll set input enter pi.
And remember when the user enters
that value into this input statement,
it will by default come out to
be a string value. So there's a
couple of variables we can use to
change our values and I'll just enter
those down here and in a comment the
actually we'll do a triple closed
string the the methods that we can
use the functions we can use are
string to change it into a string
we can use int to change something
into an int we can use float to
change something into a float um I'm
pretty sure there's bool and there's
others and then there's there's
one that could kind of determine
the best fit for you which is eval.
So let's let's do a little
demo and we'll try a
couple of these. So if I
say input enter pi then what
I can surround this whole
thing with is an eval
and then I want to print out the type
of pi and see what that gives me.
so enter pi here's 3.1415 that
is a class float okay great
what if I enter pi again and
this time I just entered the
three run my code oops I reran
my code not hitting it didn't
hit enter okay so three and
that's an integer and then let's
run it again enter pi um this
time I'm going to enter PI.
Strings don't work with eval.
I feel like they should, but
maybe I'm doing something wrong
here. So eval, I guess we'll
take this string and try to
interpret something else from it.
Let's do another quick example.
Let's just call this
name, or sorry, let's do
fave number
we'll say int input enter
your favorite number
and oh here's pi so let's do 3
.5 enter your favorite number my
favorite number is 24 just because
it's a nice number and I'll hit enter
and we didn't have a problem
there but look at what happens so
let's enter pi 3.14 if I was to
enter in let's say my favorite number
is pi and I say my favorite
number is 3.1415 we actually get a
value error that comes up because
my code was looking for an integer
value and I needed a float so it
doesn't like that and it's going to
break on mean. So this is all kind
of the idea of dynamic typing.
Maybe we should do one more
example before we're done.
Let's say I take my favorite
number and I want to
change it into a float.
So let's print out,
okay here's what we'll do.
Fave
This is great. Okay let's
print out favorite number and
then let's print it out
after we change it into
a float and let's just
notice the differences.
Okay my favorite number is 24 and oh
whoops well it looks like it didn't
change it into a float so let's
actually maybe it didn't bind to it.
Okay so now you can see in my
output that my favorite number
is not 24 it's 24.0 because
it has been changed into a
float. So this is kind of the
idea of dynamic typing, and
that wraps up this content
video. Thank you for watching.